Guide to the Walter and Emma Fong Collection
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Walter and Emma Fong collection
1889-1915
SC0994
Fong, Emma Howse.
Fong, Walter Ngon.
2 Linear feet
Photographs, manuscript materials, and printed materials related to the lives of Walter Ngon Fong (1866-1906, widely reported to be the first Chinese student to graduate from Stanford [class of 1896, A.B.]) and his wife, Emma Howse Fong.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Description of the Collection
Photographs, manuscript materials, and printed materials related to the lives of Walter Ngon Fong (1866-1906, widely reported to be the first Chinese student to graduate from Stanford [class of 1896, A.B.]) and his wife, Emma Howse Fong.
Access Terms
Fong, Emma Howse.; Fong, Emma Howse.; Fong, Walter Ngon.; Fong, Walter Ngon.; Stanford University -- General subdivision--Students.;; Chinese Americans--California.
Collection Contents
- Photographs
  - Photographs: Walter Fong portraits (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Photographs: Walter Fong portraits, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Photographs: Walter Fong portraits, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Photographs: Walter Fong and Dr. Landon, Pacific Grove, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Photographs: Walter Fong and San Jose Episcopal Mission, circa 1891 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Photographs: Emma and Walter, 1897 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Photographs: Emma and Walter, 1898 and undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Photographs: Emma and Walter and house at 1728 Delaware St. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Photographs: Walter, Emma and children (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Photographs: Walter with son Arthur Leland Fong (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Photographs: Walter with one of his children (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Photographs: Arthur Leland Fong, 1915, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Photographs: Chinese life (Box 1, Folder 13-15)
  - Photographs: Li Shing Scientific College (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Photographs: friends and family (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Photographs: Walter Fong’s grave (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Photographs: Emma and her second husband (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Photographs: Album, some images taken in Japan (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Oversize photograph of unidentified house (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Oversize photograph, group at Li Shing Scientific and Industrial College, Hong Kong, 1905 May (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Fong, Walter, “The Chinese Literary Degrees”, 1896 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Fong, Walter, “Some Phases of Village Life in Southern China”, 1903 May (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Fong, Walter: preacher’s licenses, 1893-1903 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Fong, Walter: Chinatown (S.F.) activities (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Fong, Walter: agreement and legal papers re property dispute in Oakland, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Fong, Walter: travel papers (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Fong, Walter: death records (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Clippings by or about Walter Fong (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Marriage papers of Walter Fong and Emma Howse, 1897 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Fong, Emma: Berkeley lease, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Fong, Emma, “The Closing and Opening of the Chinese Year,” typescript article (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Fong, Emma, “Sketch of the Life of the Late Rev. Walter N. Fong, M.A.”, 1906 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Kuno, Emma Fong, miscellany: 1 letter 1909 and several envelopes; membership materials for Roosevelt Memorial Association (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Kuno, Emma Fong, “My Oriental Husbands” – photocopy of essay included in Social Science Source Documents No. 4, Social Science Institute, Fisk University, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- University of the Pacific: certificate that Walter Fong completed the classical course, 1892; and ribbon from Y.M.C.A (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Stanford University: commencement items, 1896 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Stanford University, Walter Fong’s diploma, 1896 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- University of California: Commencement Program 1903, brochure on the Oriental Union, and petition of thanks from students in Fong’s class to President Wheeler (Box 2, Folder 18)
- University of California: Asiatic and Slavic Studies on the Berkeley Campus 1896-1947 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Li Shing Scientific College, assorted papers (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Map of Victoria, Hong Kong, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Chinese document (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Financial records (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Miscellany (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Memorabilia: leather wallet, ribbon Santa Clara County Union, 1897 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Lawrence, Chester (Emma Kuno’s son): invitation to the wedding of Norah Bennett to Edward B. Hussey Jr. in Tokyo, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Yu, Henry, “Mixing Bodies and Cultures: The Meaning of America’s Fascination with Sex between ‘Orientals’ and ‘Whites’” – typescript and published version of article which includes Walter and Emma Fong’s history, 1998-2001 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Berkeley High School diploma of Y. Kuno, 1890 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- University of the Pacific diploma of Walter Fong, 1892 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- M.A. diploma of Walter Fong, University of California (Box 3, Folder 3)